<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.korni22.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 17:14:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://blog.korni22.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Silos</title>
      <link>https://blog.korni22.org/posts/digital-silos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 17:14:46 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.korni22.org/posts/digital-silos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the recent months it has become more and more clear for everyone to see that putting everything in one companies&amp;rsquo; hands doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work out for &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; afterall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The probably most recent / most popular example is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google%2B#Shutdown_of_consumer_version&#34;&gt;the shutdown of Google+&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/br&gt;Of course, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.archiveteam.org&#34;&gt;ArchiveTeam&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.archiveteam.org/index.php?title=Google%2B&#34;&gt;tried to backup Google+&lt;/a&gt;, but Google &lt;em&gt;seemed&lt;/em&gt; to try and block the effort, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/textfiles/status/1112494767601053696&#34;&gt;by throttling downloads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you probably, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google%2B#Growth&#34;&gt;as most of us&lt;/a&gt;, didn&amp;rsquo;t actually use it, someone else might&amp;rsquo;ve and they might&amp;rsquo;ve used it actively.
&lt;/br&gt;Now imagine this is what you use to communicate with most of your extended family, upload vacation photos for them to enjoy and comment your cousin&amp;rsquo;s wedding announcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if Google suddenly decides that Google+ is no longer worth running and announces it&amp;rsquo;s shutdown?
This is exactly what Google did, with less than 4 months of time to do &amp;hellip; well what exactly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is basic export-functionality, but where would you move, anyway?
Facebook is, privacy-wise at as bad as Google is, and, well, social network wise, that&amp;rsquo;s about it.
The problem is, we have no realistic alternative to Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;, there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gdamdam/awesome-decentralized-web#microblogging-and-social-network&#34;&gt;decentralized alternatives&lt;/a&gt; around, but none of them have any real world usage (maybe &lt;a href=&#34;https://joinmastodon.org&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, but that might just be my filter bubble and it&amp;rsquo;s still different from being Google+ or Facebook).
&lt;a href=&#34;https://diasporafoundation.org&#34;&gt;Diaspora&lt;/a&gt; tried to achieve that years ago, but for whatever reason it never really caught on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the user there is no real alternative besides&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;move to Facebook&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;which, if you ask me, &lt;strong&gt;sucks ass&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook should&amp;rsquo;ve never gotten that big, we should&amp;rsquo;ve moved to something based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ActivityPub&#34;&gt;ActivityPub&lt;/a&gt; years ago, since it&amp;rsquo;s easy to host, easy to migrate, interoperable with other ActivityPub-based stuff and it&amp;rsquo;s getting easier to use by the minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only thing keeping me on Twitter and YouTube are the &lt;em&gt;people and their content&lt;/em&gt;, not the (mostly) shitty platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t care if YouTube satisfies the advertisers or the investors, what I care about is the new video from my favorite creator, which &lt;em&gt;just happens to be&lt;/em&gt; on YouTube, but might as well be on &lt;a href=&#34;https://joinpeertube.org/&#34;&gt;PeerTube&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://about.d.tube&#34;&gt;DTube&lt;/a&gt; or whatever (Sidenote for PeerTube: it&amp;rsquo;s based on ActivityPub as well, which means your subscriptions and creator-updates will show up just fine in your Mastodon-timeline! 🎉).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same rules, of course, apply for &lt;em&gt;checks notes&lt;/em&gt; backups as well.
A few years ago I used a service called Everpix, which I used to backup my photos. I loved it, it was fast, easy, cheap, it ticked all the boxes. But then, of course, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2013/11/5/5039216/everpix-life-and-death-inside-the-worlds-best-photo-startup&#34;&gt;it had to shut down&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;I hastily replaced it with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2014/4/17/5624890/dropbox-acquires-loom&#34;&gt;Loom&lt;/a&gt;, which was, you guessed it, shutdown after Dropbox &lt;del&gt;killed it&lt;/del&gt; shut it down &lt;em&gt;with 4 weeks notice&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, I once again scrambled to find a replacement &amp;hellip; which was &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.picturelife.com/post/109541575280/picturelife-joins-streamnation&#34;&gt;PictureLife&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/br&gt;Of course, it &lt;del&gt;got killed&lt;/del&gt; shut down as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, it&amp;rsquo;s shutdown happened after I had migrated all my stuff to Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ICloud#iCloud_Photo_Library&#34;&gt;iCloud Photo Library&lt;/a&gt;, but now all my stuff is at Apple&amp;rsquo;s mercy. If they ever shutdown (lol) or get acquired (lol), I will be in the situation I got out of just in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now once again we rely heavily on services the tech giants provide us with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;own&lt;/em&gt; our movies, we watch them on our Netflix/Prime Video/Hulu/Disney+ subscription (or which ever asshole comes up with another one by the time I have finished this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But I can still buy a digital copy of any move, dipshit!&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;Well, of course you can, but you should pray to &lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/global/video/2019/mar/07/tim-apple-donald-trump-gets-name-of-tech-giants-ceo-wrong-video&#34;&gt;Tim Apple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; Tim Cook that Apple can &lt;a href=&#34;https://discussions.apple.com/thread/5001191&#34;&gt;keep the rights forever&lt;/a&gt;, otherwise you&amp;rsquo;ve bought &lt;em&gt;jack shit&lt;/em&gt;. Yes, you get a refund, but it won&amp;rsquo;t be in cash but iTunes credit instead, so don&amp;rsquo;t even think about buying that movie on Prime Video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re always at the mercy of the original rights holder, waiting to take away things you &lt;em&gt;bought&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/br&gt;Geez, I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly imagine why people still pirate movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If companies won&amp;rsquo;t let us &lt;em&gt;legally&lt;/em&gt; own stuff in a digital way (I&amp;rsquo;m not talking about an optical disc), people will pirate what they want, the only one who get&amp;rsquo;s fucked is the lawful customer and the owner, never the pirate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I digress, back to topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to get out of &lt;em&gt;digital silos&lt;/em&gt;.
&lt;/br&gt;We need to stop using one single company and every service they offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop using Safari&amp;rsquo;s reading list, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instapaper.com&#34;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pinboard.in&#34;&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com&#34;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/br&gt;Stop using Amazon&amp;rsquo;s Kindle service, use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.defectivebydesign.org/guide/ebooks&#34;&gt;literally any other service&lt;/a&gt;, preferrably one without DRM.
&lt;/br&gt;If you can, stop using Dropbox, iCloud Drive and whatever, run a &lt;a href=&#34;https://nextcloud.com&#34;&gt;NextCloud&lt;/a&gt; instance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stop centralizing, start decentralizing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem With Tesla</title>
      <link>https://blog.korni22.org/posts/the-problem-with-tesla/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 17:51:15 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.korni22.org/posts/the-problem-with-tesla/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Continuing my true fashion of only blogging every now and then, here I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is basically my &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/nucleartakes&#34;&gt;nuclear take&lt;/a&gt; on (as the time of writing) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techmeme.com/190228/p36#a190228p36&#34;&gt;this still developing shitshow&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, what happened is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bgr.com/2016/01/07/tesla-model-3-unveiling/&#34;&gt;In March 2016&lt;/a&gt;, Elon Musk unveiled Tesla&amp;rsquo;s new car, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://3.tesla.com/&#34;&gt;Model 3&lt;/a&gt;; promising the car would &lt;em&gt;eventually&lt;/em&gt; cost around $35,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;later &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/elonmusk/status/697682665919516672&#34;&gt;doubling down on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; (as a true CEO does) that it would cost &amp;ldquo;around&amp;rdquo; $35,000 from the start&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;and deliveries would &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.fo/YCUdw&#34;&gt;start late 2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As Tesla is known to do, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2017-10-02/tesla-sales-climb-as-model-3-stokes-demand-in-pricier-offerings&#34;&gt;they, of course, delayed deliveries&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/innovations/wp/2017/11/03/sleepless-nights-broken-robots-and-mounting-pressure-musk-offers-rare-glimpse-inside-teslas-production-hell/?noredirect=on&#34;&gt;four more months&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://electrek.co/2017/07/17/teslat-model-3-delivery-event-invites-owners/&#34;&gt;They did, however, deliver the first 30 cars on July 28th 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally though, Elon got production ramped up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://ir.tesla.com/static-files/7235e525-db16-470c-8dce-9ecac0ad7712&#34;&gt;55,840 cars in the third quarter of 2018&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deliveries are going fairly smooth nowadays, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tesla_Model_3#Issues&#34;&gt;ignoring any of this&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/asfalcone/status/1090626168171253760&#34;&gt;or this&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://electrek.co/2018/01/01/tesla-releases-automatic-wiper-update-beta/&#34;&gt;any of this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, back to present.
As I write this, it&amp;rsquo;s the 1st of March, 2019.
Late yesterday, Tesla finally announced the availability of the once promised $35,000 Model 3, only a mere &lt;em&gt;7 months&lt;/em&gt; after deliveries started (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tesla.com/blog/35000-Tesla-model-3-available-now?redirect=no&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the official announcement&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rejoice, right?
Well, not so fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What they announced was not only the much anticipated cheaper version &lt;del&gt;something something &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Volkswagen&#34;&gt;people&amp;rsquo;s car&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;, they also announced&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Model 3 Standard Range Plus, 240 miles of range, top speed of 140 mph, 0-60 mph in 5.3 seconds and most premium interior features at $37,000 before incentives. For 6% more money, you get 9% more range, more power, and an upgraded interior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider me impressed, anything else?
&lt;/br&gt;Of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve these prices while remaining financially sustainable, Tesla is shifting sales worldwide to online only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uhm, wait a minute, what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also making it much easier to try out and return a Tesla, so that a test drive prior to purchase isn’t needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note what they say, specifically:
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t test-drive a Tesla anymore.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily just buy one, see?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also making it much easier to try out and return a Tesla, so that a test drive prior to purchase isn’t needed. You can now return a car within 7 days or 1,000 miles for a full refund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Of course Elon, I&amp;rsquo;ll just get a &amp;gt;=$35,000 loan, drive the car for a week and give it back if I don&amp;rsquo;t like it&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/br&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fuck&lt;/em&gt;, no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They will also remove most stores and convert some to showrooms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months, we will be winding down many of our stores, with a small number of stores in high-traffic locations remaining as galleries, showcases and Tesla information centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; consider this very impressive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we will be increasing our investment in the Tesla service system, with the goal of same-day, if not same-hour service, and with most service done by us coming to you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But keep in mind what Marco Arment, Tumblr co-founder, founder of Instapaper and Overcast &lt;em&gt;and owner of a Model S&lt;/em&gt; has to say:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Same-hour service isn’t going to help when the parts they need are backordered for months. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/33qGVamoRA&#34;&gt;https://t.co/33qGVamoRA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Marco Arment (@marcoarment) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/marcoarment/status/1101279792530407424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;March 1, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, I consider this the wrong decision.
What Tesla desperately need was &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; scale, &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; delivered cars, &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; service infrastructure and as many test drives as possible to get &lt;em&gt;as many&lt;/em&gt; interested customers as possible.
&lt;/br&gt;I know literally no one who would ever buy a car without being able to test-drive one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Tesla_Bear&#34;&gt;Someone&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; smarter than me started a &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Tesla_Bear/status/1100520637540564994&#34;&gt;fantastic thread&lt;/a&gt;, collection various aspects and owners opions about this, after analyzing the whole situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, for the love of whatever you consider holy, read the &lt;em&gt;entire&lt;/em&gt; thread and come back here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, now think about what you just heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this sound like a company you&amp;rsquo;d be willing to give a hefty amount of money for a car you&amp;rsquo;ve never driven before?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Tesla is able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate a massive amount of hype for a very expensive product&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build an amazing electric drive train and power supply for that drivetrain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build passenger cars that &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/gOuOulH02bs?t=201&#34;&gt;go &lt;em&gt;crazy fast&lt;/em&gt; down the quarter mile&lt;/a&gt; (10.79 seconds)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Tesla, seemingly, is not able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zdnet.com/article/new-ntsb-tesla-fatal-crash-report-model-s-battery-reignited-twice-after-florida-crash/&#34;&gt;build a battery that doesn&amp;rsquo;t catch fire after crashing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://insideevs.com/tesla-model-3-rear-bumper-rain/&#34;&gt;build a car that doesn&amp;rsquo;t loose body parts after driving through water&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/9vmmR3P58gs&#34;&gt;that get&amp;rsquo;s wet inside when it rains&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;build a car &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/asfalcone/status/1090626168171253760&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/5PU0Kbo5Tos&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;functioning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/teslamotors/comments/6giiao/my_model_x_90d_driver_side_falcon_door_opened_on/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;doors&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, I admire what they do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I even &lt;em&gt;test-drove&lt;/em&gt; a P85+, back when it was the fastest Model S, during their &lt;a href=&#34;https://translate.google.com/translate?hl=&amp;amp;sl=de&amp;amp;tl=en&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.autoextrem.de%2Fartikel-news%2F1063-tesla-model-s-probefahrten-9-orten-deutschland-fully-charged-tour.html&#34;&gt;fully charged&lt;/a&gt; tour through Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;loved&lt;/em&gt; it.
&lt;/br&gt;I enjoyed driving this massive, fairly luxurious, heavy car, that despite all that, would accelerate like a proper sports car, it even almost drove like one all around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all I see nowadays is how bad Tesla is at scaling and how good Elon is at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-tesla-results-reaction/tesla-must-stop-overpromising-could-need-more-finance-analysts-idUSKBN1D21A3&#34;&gt;over-promising and under-delivering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would have been a happy camper if Tesla came out of nowhere and just left a burning mess of the slow, boring shitshow that (most of) the automotive industry really is.
&lt;/br&gt;But it seems Tesla just wants to build cars for people who &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy&lt;/em&gt; cars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federated Networks, Free Speech and Other Easy Topics</title>
      <link>https://blog.korni22.org/posts/federated-networks-free-speech-and-other-easy-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 13:06:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.korni22.org/posts/federated-networks-free-speech-and-other-easy-topics/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Okay, today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about a&lt;del&gt;n easy&lt;/del&gt; topic that probably has been discussed a million times in the last few weeks by people &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; smarter than I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, some of you might actually care about someone else&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alex_Jones&#34;&gt;Alex Jones&lt;/a&gt; has been all over every kind of media outlet, because his &lt;del&gt;fish oil shop&lt;/del&gt; conspiracy website &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/InfoWars&#34;&gt;InfoWars&lt;/a&gt; was banned from two &lt;del&gt;kinda&lt;/del&gt; important websites: YouTube and Facebook.
Since he &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; allowed to say whatever he wants and deems worth saying, I don&amp;rsquo;t recognize this as censorship or a free speech violation.
Facebook and ~YouTube~ Alphabet are private companies and can decide for themselves who they deem &amp;ldquo;worthy&amp;rdquo; of their platform and its users. And, for that matter, so is InfoWars, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kjmci/status/1026896388003704832&#34;&gt;which is why they reservce their rights to ban you, if you violate their policies&lt;/a&gt; and virtually agree with me 🙃&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might think otherwise and it&amp;rsquo;s completely fine and up to you.
If I were Facebook and Alphabet, I would&amp;rsquo;ve made the same decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notably absent from the list above is &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.
Twitter is arguably just as important as Facebook and YouTube are, but Twitter&amp;rsquo;s CEO &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Dorsey&#34;&gt;Jack Dorsey&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wsj.com/articles/inside-twitters-long-slow-struggle-to-police-bad-actors-1535972402&#34;&gt;supposedly overruled&lt;/a&gt; the moderation-teams decision to ban Alex Jones (Disclaimer: &lt;a href=&#34;https://eu.usatoday.com/story/tech/news/2018/09/04/twitter-jack-dorsey-alex-jones-infowars/1188812002/&#34;&gt;he denies that&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alex Jones, in this case, is nothing more than a recent and controversial example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ask me, everybody should be allowed to say what they want — inside of legal boundaries — e.g. denying the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Holocaust&#34;&gt;Holocaust&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laws_against_Holocaust_denial&#34;&gt;is flat out &lt;em&gt;illegal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in 17 countries (including Germany).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone claims the sky is green instead of blue, they should totally be allowed to say that. &lt;em&gt;But&lt;/em&gt; I have no legal obligations to give those people a possibility to talk about this on &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are platforms that allow free speech according to the American law, e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gab_(social_network)&#34;&gt;gab.ai&lt;/a&gt;.
Basically since day one, gab.ai is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gab_(social_network)#Users&#34;&gt;toxic cesspool full of xenophobes and white supremacists that have been banned from other websites&lt;/a&gt; — &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thedailybeast.com/conspiracy-theories-are-eating-this-alt-right-friendly-site-from-the-inside&#34;&gt;and some users have turned against the site&amp;rsquo;s creator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mastodon, the decentralized, federated and FOSS alternative to the existing &lt;del&gt;birdsite&lt;/del&gt; microblogging service Twitter is — of course — not immune to this problem, why would it be?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, I consider Mastodon&amp;rsquo;s (or any other federated social network) a better solution for this problem, since you can&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a) choose any existing instance (&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.korni22.org/posts/mastodon-in-docker-and-aws/&#34;&gt;like mine!&lt;/a&gt;) that might have rules that suit your views better &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;b) even run your own instance to have your own rules and code of conduct &lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s federated, you can connect with users on other instances, with other code of conducts &lt;del&gt;(codes of conduct? codes of conducts?)&lt;/del&gt; while not having to rely on some big tech giant&amp;rsquo;s website &lt;del&gt;that is censored because of it&amp;rsquo;s leftist agenda&lt;/del&gt; that &lt;del&gt;censored you&lt;/del&gt; banned you, because you violated their community policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, no social network is &lt;em&gt;immune&lt;/em&gt; to hate speech, racism or whatever you consider bad behavior. No, not even federated ones, be it &lt;a href=&#34;https://joinmastodon.org&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pleroma.social&#34;&gt;Pleroma&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://gnu.io/social/&#34;&gt;GNU social&lt;/a&gt;. Not because they are flawed and nobody actually cares, but because our societies are not immune to it. No amount of &lt;del&gt;business bullshit like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_data&#34;&gt;Big Data&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blockchain&#34;&gt;Blockchains&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence&#34;&gt;AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt; technology can solve this problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The only thing you can do is create clear, easy to understandable guidelines, follow them and enforce them if need be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;update-from-september-7th-2018&#34;&gt;Update from September 7th, 2018&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twiter &lt;em&gt;obviously&lt;/em&gt; read my blog post and finally acted accordingly:
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; data-cards=&#34;hidden&#34; data-lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Today, we permanently suspended &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/RealAlexJones&#34;&gt;@realalexjones&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/infowars&#34;&gt;@infowars&lt;/a&gt; from Twitter and Periscope. We took this action based on new reports of Tweets and videos posted yesterday that violate our abusive behavior policy, in addition to the accounts’ past violations. &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/gckzUAV8GL&#34;&gt;https://t.co/gckzUAV8GL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Twitter Safety (@TwitterSafety) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TwitterSafety/status/1037804427992686593?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;September 6, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;Hint: if you are a white supremacist, holocaust denier or any other kind of idiot, please stay away from ffm.social, or we&amp;rsquo;ll ban you.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;If you run an instance, that does things differently and allows free speech (in the american way), it is very likely that you&amp;rsquo;ll end up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tootcafe/blocked-instances&#34;&gt;this list&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon in Docker and AWS</title>
      <link>https://blog.korni22.org/posts/mastodon-in-docker-and-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 14:46:02 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.korni22.org/posts/mastodon-in-docker-and-aws/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By now, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely heard about &lt;a href=&#34;https://joinmastodon.org&#34;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;, which is all the rage right now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is, functionality wise, a (almost) perfect replacement for ~~the birdsite~ &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.
Lately, Twitter has become a cesspool infested with people that I do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; want in my &lt;del&gt;filter bubble&lt;/del&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/korni22/following&#34;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Mastodon is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Federation_(information_technology)&#34;&gt;federated&lt;/a&gt; one &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; run their own instance. Running stuff is hard though, especially in production and becomes exponentially harder if more people start using it.
And since I wanted to have &lt;del&gt;my own&lt;/del&gt; a Mastodon instance as well, I was looking for a reliable solution, that takes as much work away from me as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, this means having a Linux VM that needs little to maintenance (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.debian.org&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt; instead of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.archlinux.org&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;, e.g.), runs &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com&#34;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/swarm/&#34;&gt;Swarm&lt;/a&gt; so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to care about scaling, load balancing, routing , running &lt;code&gt;docker-compose up -d&lt;/code&gt; after reboots and using &lt;del&gt;someone else&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/del&gt; a hosted &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relational_database&#34;&gt;RDS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, to be precise, I am talking about running Mastodon on top of&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a Docker Swarm (with 1 node)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;utilizing Amazon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/en/ec2/&#34;&gt;EC2&lt;/a&gt; &lt;code&gt;t3.medium&lt;/code&gt; and RDS for &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/en/rds/postgresql/&#34;&gt;PostgreSQL&lt;/a&gt;, on a &lt;code&gt;db.t2.small&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;cache.t2.micro&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/en/elasticache/&#34;&gt;ElastiCache&lt;/a&gt; as &lt;a href=&#34;https://redis.io&#34;&gt;Redis&lt;/a&gt; replacement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with 50 GB &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/en/ebs/&#34;&gt;EBS&lt;/a&gt; volume for &lt;del&gt;your&lt;/del&gt; the user&amp;rsquo;s assets and uploads&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;with &lt;a href=&#34;https://traefik.io&#34;&gt;Træfik&lt;/a&gt; as a reverse proxy, that also manages &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt; certificates for me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this setup, I only care about significant OS updates, Mastodon updates are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tootsuite/documentation/blob/master/Running-Mastodon/Docker-Guide.md#updating&#34;&gt;fairly simple&lt;/a&gt;, storage and database are (update-wise) none of my business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is, sadly, not a cheap setup, comes in at a steep ~80€/month, but it&amp;rsquo;s your instance afterwards, with &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; rules, &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; choices and full control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want, I have &lt;del&gt;unlimited&lt;/del&gt; a few &lt;a href=&#34;https://ffm.social/invite/BsgQHz8p&#34;&gt;invites to spare&lt;/a&gt; 😉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to make things easier for &lt;del&gt;future generations&lt;/del&gt; &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ll publish my configurations in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Korni22/mastodon-aws&#34;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt;. Also, I might at some point add a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.terraform.io&#34;&gt;Terraform&lt;/a&gt; template to make things easier 😎.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>